# **ADAM BOUDJEMAA**

## LEAD DEV BLOCKCHAIN / HEAD OF BLOCKCHAIN

+971 58 512 9533 | boudjemaa.adam@gmail.com

## **PROFILE SUMMARY**

Lead blockchain developer experienced in smart-contract design and deployment on platforms such as Ethereum, Binance, Fantom, and Polygon. Co-author of ERC3643 standard for Security-Tokens. Deployed hack-proof smart-contracts worth over \$10M while ensuring business requirements. Proficient in security-wise development with tools like Fuzz and Mutation Testing, Echidna, and Vertigo. Led team of 10 engineers ensuring top-quality development, security, and testing practices

#### **CORE SKILLS & COMPETENCES**

- Experienced in developing Solidity and smart-contracts for EVM-platforms including Ethereum, Binance, Fantom, and Polygon.
- Proficient in fuzz and mutation testing, Echidna and Vertigo for security development
- Expertise in Web3.js and Ethers.js to communicate with blockchain networks and smart-contracts.
- Led a team of 10 full-stack and smart-contract engineers to ensure project coordination, delivery, and coordinating project activities
- Conducted thorough code reviews and authored technical documentation, leading to the successful deployment of over 500 hack-proof contracts on various platforms.

## **ACHIEVEMENTS**

- Deployed over \$50M worth of hack-proof smart-contracts and 500+ smart-contracts across 10+ blockchain.
- Co-authored the **ERC-3643** Standard, contributing to developing of a widely recognized blockchain industry standard [https://tokeny.com/erc3643/].
- Invented complete dynamic NFT ("dNFT") solution based on ERC-721 and ERC-1155 standards.
- Launched "StakingPlatform" smart-contract to Fantom [FTM], Polygon [MATIC], and Binance Chain [BNB] with 15 successful deployments.
- Created Centralized and Decentralized Finance 10+ CeFi, CeDeFi and DeFi protocols such as Aave, Compound and Yearn.
- Improved the existing SFC (Special Fee Contract) to facilitate distribution of rewards to Stakers (Delegators and Validators) on Fantom, while optimizing gas usage and reducing transaction costs by 40%.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# LEAD BLOCKCHAIN DEVELOPER

#### **SEPTEMBER 2021 - PRESENT**

Polytrade, Dubai, United Arab Emirates

- Led the design, architecture, end-to-end implementation of complete CeDeFi and DeFi solutions, and deployment of on EVM L2, overseeing assets exceeding \$12,000,000 TVL.
- Prioritized security by implementing rigorous Solidity code, carrying out fuzz testing, and conducting in-house audits.
- Led the development of the EIP-6960 (Dual Layer Token standard), setting a new benchmark for token standards.
- Architected and built a Real-World Asset (RWA) Marketplace, integrating real-world assets into DeFi.
- Created multiple lending pools with Bonding curves, providing innovative lending solutions in DeFi.
- Developed APIs using Node.js, Fastify, and Express frameworks.
- Designed and developed 10+ CeDeFi contracts using Solidity, Foundry, Hardhat, and Yul assembly.
- Directed the deployment on AWS EC2 and AWS Lambda using AWS Secrets Manager.

#### HEAD OF BLOCKCHAIN MARCH 2020 - PRESENT

Retreeb, Switzerland

- Collaborated with 3 external security auditors, including Certik, Hacken, and ImmuneBytes, to conduct 5 audits and address potential security loopholes, vulnerabilities, and threats.
- Designed and executed Retreeb's blockchain strategy, resulting in a top 3 ranking on the Fantom blockchain and recognition in the community with top search trends on Coingecko and Coinmarketcap.
- Managed 3 projects from conception to implementation, achieving on-time delivery, within budget, and increased customer satisfaction ratings.
- Deployed the "StakingPlatform" smart contract 15 times on Fantom (FTM), Polygon (MATIC), and Binance Chain (BNB), resulting in the locking of over \$20M in total value locked (TVL).
- Conceptualized strategic plans to re-establish ethics and solidarity in the financial system using Blockchain.
- Benchmarked and optimized blockchain infrastructures, resulting in less than 1s time to finality using Fantom blockchain and significant reduction in gas costs for smart-contracts.

# **BLOCKCHAIN ENGINEER**

# FEBRUARY 2021 – SEPTEMBER 2021

Securrency, Abu Dhabi, United Arab Emirates

- Incorporated the latest possible industry enhancements and integrations to continuously enhance the quality and functionality of the project.
- Performed comprehensive code reviews to ensure adherence to industry standards.
- Modernised the design and implementation of cross-compatible security token protocols CAT-20 and CAT-721.
- Researched and evaluated Layer2 scaling solutions, including Optimism and Arbitrum protocols.
- Designed and developed applications and achieved an 70% increase in speed and performance on the DAPP.

#### **BLOCKCHAIN DEVELOPER AUGUST 2020 - FEBRUARY 2021**

Fantom Foundation

- Created a Nifty fork on Fantom for NFT trading and managed the NFT game PoC using the ERC-721 Standard.
- Built dApps and smart-contracts using Solidity, Hardhat, and Web3.js/ethers.js libraries. Influenced and guided in the development of fSwap and Keep3r open-source projects with Andre Cronje.
- Realized a decentralized secure wallet (multi-sig) apps forking Gnosis protocol.
- Implemented a Bitcoin Bet smart contract using Chainlink VRF and Band Oracles for real-time pricing.

## **BLOCKCHAIN DEVELOPER** OCTOBER 2019 – FEBRUARY 2021

Tokeny Solutions, Luxembourg

- Implemented smart-contracts on Ethereum (T-REX, ERC-20, ERC-724, ERC-735, and ERC-1400.
- Designed systems for managing identity on Blockchain and controlled Blockchain integration using libraries such as Web3 and Ethers.js.
- Conducted unit testing, continuous integration, process experience, and test-driven development (TDD) with Jest.
- Managed EVM, Dapps, ERC20 tokens, ICO, Web3, and full development of the T-Rex standard (ERC-3643).

## **ADDITIONAL WORK EXPERIENCES**

**BLOCKCHAIN DEVELOPER** APRIL 2019 - SEPTEMBER 2019 Flexper, France

**BLOCKCHAIN DEVELOPER MAY 2018 - FEBRUARY 2019** Equisafe, Paris

**BLOCKCHAIN DEVELOPER NOVEMBER 2018 - JANUARY 2019** BTU Protocol, Paris Area, France

IT SECURITY ENGINEER **NOVEMBER 2017 - NOVEMBER 2018** ArcelorMittal, Luxembourg

**CONSULTANT AND FOUNDER** SEPTEMBER 2014 - MARCH 2016 Digital Blockchain Technology, Paris

**WEB DEVELOPER** SEPTEMBER 2012 – DECEMBER 2013 Saint Germain en Lave

## **EXPERTISE**

- Blockchain development
- **Smart-contracts**
- Decentralized apps (dApps)
- Cryptography
- **Project Management**
- Research and Analysis
- **Decentralized Applications**
- Code Testing
- Project Architecturing
- CI/CD Principles
- Team leadership
- Programming (Solidity, JavaScript)

## **EDUCATIONAL EXPERIENCE**

# **COMPUTER SOFTWARE ENGINEERING PROGRAM** 42 School, Paris, France

2014-2018

- · Completed a rigorous, project-based program in C, shell, low-level programming, PHP, C++, and JavaScript.
- Built a virtual machine (VM), focusing on low-level code, debugging, and memory management.
- Enhanced cybersecurity skills through Root-me challenges (offensive security) and top 10 OWASP exercises.
- Performed peer-to-peer (p2p) reviews and feedback to enhance teamwork and communication skills.

## **BLOCKCHAIN BASICS**

University of Buffalo & The State University of New York

## **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

- Solidity
- JavaScript / Typescript
- Node.js
- React
- **Smart-Contracts Ethereum**
- Amazon Web Services (AWS)